Guide to the Oversize Manuscripts Collection 1648-2014 MS OS
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Individual Oversize Manuscripts, 1648-1942
  - [Y-1817] Patents and Descriptions- Orange Webb (Contains Presidential Signature), circa 1817 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1819] Grim- Notes on City Hall (Photostats) (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1819] Grim- Notes on City Hall (Originals) (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1823] Peter Smith Conveyance (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1823, May] Corporation for the Relief of Widows, 1823 May 3 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-1829] Ship Extio (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1829, August] Maxwell, Hugh, 1829 August 22 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1831] John James Audubon Bird Descriptions (Oversize small)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Gift of Dr. Thomas Perry, Jr., 1983 or 1984
  - [Y-1833, December] Resolution of Anti-Slavery Convention, 1833 December 6 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1834] Riots (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1835, October] Isaac Bush Letter, 1835 October 30 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1835, November] Whaleman's Shipping Paper (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1836, January] John Parker Certificate- Texas, 1836 January 26 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1836, July] Peake, Frederick L., 1836 July 1 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1837] Audubon, John James- List of Birds of America (Oversize large)
  - [Y-1839, November 20] Corporation for Relief of Widows (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1840] U.S. Navy Fire Bill (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1840, December] Election Certificate, 1840 December 2 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1844] Meteorological Register (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1845] Breed and Bowne- Certificate of Marriage (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1845] Meteorological Register (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1846] Meteorological Register (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1848] Meteorological Register (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1850] Coroner's Account (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1850, January, September] Lind-Barnum Preliminary Agreement and Final Contract, 1850 January 9, September 14 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1853] Brown, Jesse- Diploma (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1853, October] Castle Garden- Poem (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1856] Schwartzwalder, Ameia (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1857] Subscription List to the Numismatical History of the U.S. (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1858] Marriage Certificate- Salem H. Smith and Lucy Bassler (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1860] Certificate that Accompanied Bullet Mold (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1861] Wilde, Edward S. (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1861, July] Murray, Robert, 1861 July 22 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1862] Ericsson, John- Resolution by New York State Assembly (Oversize medium)
    NHSC- John Ericsson Collection, 1831-1893 (bulk 1862-1888)
  - [Y-1862, May] Sketch of a Military Reconnaissance- Portsmouth, 1862 May 27-29 (Oversize medium)
    NHSC- General James Barnes Collection, 1827-1993
  - [Y-1862] Map of the Rebel Intrenched Camp near Norfolk (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1862] National Academy of Design (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1862] Conover family certificates, 1862-1894 (Oversize small)
    Includes 8 documents: 2 graduation certificates from Rutgers Female Institute to Lizzie A. Conover (1862, 1865); Certificate of membership in the Free and Accepted Masons, Holland Lodge, No. 8, to John T. Conover (1864); Graduation certificate from Van Norman Institute to Mary Conover Jones (1888); Graduation certificate from Columbia College, School of Mines, to Edward Marwedel Jones (1894); and 3 oval pictures (drawings?) of John, Lizzie, Mary (identified by donor; not noted on the objects). (Gift, Richard K. Lewis, 2019)
  - [Y-1863] Emancipation Proclamation (Leland-Boker Autographed Edition) (Oversize small)
    Contains Presidential Signature
  - [Y-1863, March] Swartwout, George H., 1863 March 17 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1863, December] Couring, Rufus B.- Attorney Appointment, 1863 December 8 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1864, May] National Academy of Design, 1864 May 11 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-undated] My Friends at Libby Prison [certificate signed by prisoners], circa 1860s (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1865, April] NYC Chamber of Commerce- Memorial to A. Lincoln, 1865 April 22 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-1865 May] Presidential Pardons of Confederate Soldiers (George Cronan, N.S. Rector, R.A. Rutherford), 1865 May 5, 12 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1867] Sturges Testimonial (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1871] Key, Calvin Jones- Diplomas (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1872, May] Meteorological Record, 1872 May 29 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1874, November] Sigel, Franz- Testimonial, 1874 November 18 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1875] Isaac Peck Family Papers (Oversize small)
    Isaac Peck family papers, 1799-1907 (bulk 1830-1890)Emma Thursby papers, 1706-1940 (bulk 1880-1920
  - [Y-1878] Crommelin Family Tree (Oversize large)
  - [Y-1879] Thursby, Emma (Oversize small)
    Emma Thursby papers, 1706-1940 (bulk 1880-1920)
  - [Y-1880] Osgood, Harris and Co. (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1883] Stevens, J.A.- Evacuation Day Celebration (Oversize medium)
    Papers, 1811-1885- John Austin Stevens
  - [Y-1884] Electoral Votes (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1885] Mabbott, J. Milton (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1885] Thursby, Emma (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1886] New York State Society of Cincinnati- Howe, George B. (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1893] Ward, Aaron - Certificate, Society of Colonial Wars (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1896, May] Austin, Mary North, 1896 May 12 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1898] Sherman, Thomas G. - Passport, 1898 June 18 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1899, March] Helen M. Gould, 1899 March 24 (Oversize small)
    Helen Miller Gould Shepard papers, 1814-1941
  - [Y-1900] Tuller, Loren W.- Military Certificate (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1904] Helen M. Gould, China Testimonial (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-1905, December] Bonaparte, Charles Joseph, 1905 December 7 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1907-1908] Sara Hoexter Blumenthal (Oversize small)
    Sara Hoexter Blumenthal papers, 1910-1951
  - [Y-1914, December] Harbord, James, 1914 December 31 (Oversize small)
    Related Materials
    James Harbord Papers and BV Harbord
  - [Y-1919] Arthur M. Anderson (Oversize small)
  - [Y-1931] Gardner Institute (New York) diploma to Nina Woods Parke, 1931 June 5 (Oversize small)
    Certificate awarded for the completion of studies in the College Preparatory Course. Signed by principal Mary Elizabeth Masland. Stamped with seal that reads "The Gardner School, 1857." With tied ribbon that was presumably used to hold the document in rolled form. (Historical note: Also know as the Gardner School for Girls, the organization was founded in 1857. At the time of this certificate, and since 1916, it was located at 11 East 51st Street in New York City. Masland had been its principal since 1910. The Institute closed in 1949.)
    Gift of Nina Hill Hopkins, September 2018.
  - [Y-1942] Zenger Memorial Fund (Oversize small)
  - [Y-undated] Rules of NYC Firemen (Oversize small)
- Series II. Oversize Manuscripts From Other Collections, 1714-2006
  - [Y-AHMC Arndt, Abraham] Commision to Abraham Arndt Esqauire as first Judge of the County of Montgomery, 1801 January 24 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Ashmun, George] Portrait and letter, 1841 November 6, undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Brookes Family] Deeds and mortgages, 1751-1802 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-AHMC Brooklyn, NY] Abstract of Title, Maps, 1801-1856 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-AHMC Brookman, Thomas] Writ, 1762 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Buffalo, NY] Improvement of Roads, Accounts, 1812-1814 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Buffalo, NY] Harbor Construction, Payroll, 1838-1839 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Charlotte County, N.Y.] Land Grant, 1772 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Coenties Slip] Deeds, 1756-1792 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-AHMC Colebrooke & Rogers] Account book, 1729 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Cooper, Isaac] Deed for land in Bangor, 1815 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Cothonneau, William] Estate inventory, 1718 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Davey, Peter] Eagle Fire Company Insurance Policy, 1806 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Eaton, Charles P] Photograph (2 copies), undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Howell, Jacob] Receipt roll of Howell's Company, Farrington's Regiment, 1814 October 22 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Jamaica (West Indies)] Indenture between Eilardus Westerlo, Catherine Westerlo, and Richard Grant, for a sugar plantation, 1784 July 6 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-AHMC Johnson, William M.] Map and deed, 1845 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Kroaker] Handwritten newspaper from Lyme, Conn., 1873 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-AHMC Long Island City (New York, N.Y.)] Lawrence family deeds, 1639-1759 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-AHMC McConnell, James] Legal documents for assignment of a judgment, 1816 August 26 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC McFarlan, Robert] Commission as judge in the Court of Common Pleas, Montgomery County, N.Y., 1798 March 27 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC McKune, Robert] Letters patent as a repacker, inspector of beef and culler of staves in Orange County, N.Y.], 1803 January 15 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Melyn Papers] Mandamus, 1648 April 25 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Morse, Samuel F.B.] Drawing of first register for Morse's magnetic telegraph), 1846 (Oversize small)
    General Note
    Drawn and signed by John Stokell, New York. Signed as presented to N-YHS by William Davis, July 1852.
  - [Y-AHMC Mott, Valentine] Diplomas & certificates, 1806-1833 [4 items: one in folder + three in frames] (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Smith, John (active 18th century)] Family papers, 1774-1801 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Stevens, William H.] Appointment as Consul General, 1901 May 13 (Oversize small)
    Access Restrictions
    Contains President William McKinley's signature. Includes two envelopes.
  - [Y-AHMC Stuyvesant deed] Peter Stuyvesant deed to Govert Loockermans, 1664 May 20 (Oversize small)
    Includes a frame made of wood from the famed pear tree Stuyvesant planted at what became the northeast corner of Third Avenue and East 13th Street in Manhattan. For fuller details, and to request these items for research, read their catalog record.
  - [Y-AHMC Wood, Fernando] "To the People of Louisiana, their Executive and Representatives... " (appointment and certification of New York City's Commissioners to the South), 1861 January 29 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Yorkville Clock], Neighbors Restoring the Historic Yorkville Clock records, 1998 (Oversize medium)
    Folder 3 of 3. Includes the three elevations and detail plans for the clock refurbishment prepared by Historical Arts & Casting.
  - [Y- Arnold, Abraham and Percy], 1897-1918 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Astor Family Papers], 1790-1877 (Oversize small, medium, large)
    Other Finding Aids
    See Astor Family Papers finding aid for further information on oversize manuscripts from this collection.
  - [Y-Banyar Family Papers] (Oversize small, medium, large)
    Other Finding Aids Note
    See Goldsboro Banyar and Banyar Family Papers finding aid for further information on oversize materials from this collection.
  - [Y-Belknap, Waldron Papers] Documents, 1816-1843 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Belknap, Waldron Papers] Print of Government House, 1902 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Bernheimer, Charles L. Papers, MS 58], 1916-1936 (Oversize medium)
    Oversize items from the Charles L. Bernheimer papers, MS 58. See the finding aid for that collection for content description.
  - [Y-Bible and Fruit Mission Society, MS 59], 1877, 1900, 1950 (Oversize small)
    3 items removed from Society records. See MS 59 finding aid
  - [Y-Bowers Family Papers], 1748-1777 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Bowers Family Papers] Genealogy Materials, 1944, Undated (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Bowers Family Papers] Leases, 1714-1789 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Bradish, Luther. Papers, MS 71] Various documents (2 folders), 1800s (Oversize medium)
    2 folders of oversize documents from the Bradish papers, MS 71; see the Bradish finding aid for details.
  - [Y-Brown Brothers Harriman] 100th Anniversary Dinner Seating Plan, 1925 December 18 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Brown Brothers Harriman] Group Portrait, US/UK Conference; Exterior Photos BBH Building, 1941, c.1960 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Brown Brothers Harriman] Headstone Plans- Greenwood Cemetery, 1939 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Brown Brothers Harriman] James Crosby Brown Estate, 1934 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Brown Brothers Harriman] Mary Brown's Estate, Will, Maps, 1922-1927 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Brown Brothers Harriman] National City Bank Building Plans, 1929 January (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Brown Brothers Harriman] New Wall Street Building: Delano Correspondence- Plans, 1923-1926 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Brown Brothers Harriman] W. Averill Harriman- Chicago Sun Tribune: 21st Birthday Feature, 1911 April 27 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Browne Family Papers] Deeds, 1751-1802 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Caledonian Club] Photographs (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Canon-Cannon-Canoune] Correspondence, 1906-1909 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Canon-Cannon-Canoune] Newspaper Clippings, 1932-1953 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Certificates] Mechanick Society- John Cameron, 1803 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Certificates] Miscellaneous, 1795-1968 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Certificates] Miscellaneous, 1862-1967 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Certificates] Miscellaneous, 1872-1908 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Certificates] German Society of N.Y., 1785 October 3 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Certificates] Garibaldi Statue in Washington Square Park, 1888 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Certificates] Post, 1835-1864 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Certificates] Post, 1864-1921 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Certificates] U.S.S. Wasp / H.M.S. Frolic, 1812 December 31 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Clark, Donald F., Collection] Deeds for Kingston, NY, 1717 February 20; 1722 March 2 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Clark, Donald F., Collection] Americae Pars Meridionalis (map), circa 1650 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Coke, John A. Papers] Book Recording Circulars, 1863-1864 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Coke, John A. Papers] Endorsement Book, 1864-1865 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Coke, John A. Papers] List of Retails and Exemptions, Richmond County, 13th Congressional District, 1862 December (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Confederate States of America] Confederate Army Records, 1861-1865 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Cunningham, Bill. MS 3137], 1998-2014 (Oversize small)
    Oversize items from the Bill Cunningham collection, MS 3137. See the finding aid for that collection for content description.
  - [Y-Carole De Saram Papers (MS 3059)], 1978-2006 (Oversize small)
    See finding aid for Carole De Saram papers (MS 3059) for details on oversize content.
  - [Y-Delafield Family] Photostats, Undated (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Drive to Protect the Ladies Mile Historic District] Supporting Research, book proofs and article (4 folders) (Oversize small)
  - [Y- Duane Family Papers] Leases, Duanesburg, 1765-1797 (Oversize small)
  - [Y- Duane Family Papers] Leases, Duanesburg, 1803-1837 (Oversize small)
  - [Y- Duane Family Papers] Surrenders and Grants, Duanesburg, 1791-1831 (Oversize small)
  - [Y- Duane Family Papers] Legal papers and notes, Duanesburg, Undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y- Duane Family Papers] Legal documents and papers, Princetown, Albany County, 1765 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y- Duane Family Papers] Legal documents and papers, Princetown, Albany County, 1731-1748 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y- Duane Family Papers] Legal documents and papers, Ulster County, 1735-1754 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y- Duane Family Papers] Legal documents and papers, Socialborough, 1767-1775 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Elmira 1948 Election Study (MS 196)] Maps (2 of 2) (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Erving-King Papers] Documents, 1804-1931, Undated (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Erving-King Papers] Geneological Charts, Undated (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Erving-King Papers] Maps, 1789-1934, Undated (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Facsimilies] Miscellaneous, Undated (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Fairchild, Charles S.] Diplomas and Photograph, 1887-1929 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Falk, Myron, Papers (MS 3047)], 1923-1944 (Oversize small)
    Scope and Contents Note
    Includes various oversize items from the Myron Falk papers. See the Falk finding aid for details.
  - [Y-Falk, Myron, Papers (MS 3047)], 1913-1930 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Goldstone, Harmon Hendricks], 1941-1985 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Fox,Gustavus Vasa Collection] Commissions, Certificate of Appointment, and Passport, 1852-1871 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Friend of City Hall Park], 1998 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Fulton, Robert Papers] Indenture with Christiana Morris for property on Reed Street, 1810 May 30 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Gates, Horatio Papers] Commission, 1775 June 19 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Gates, Horatio Papers] Pay and Rations of the U.S. Army, 1776 December 31 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Gates, Horatio Papers] Returns, 1778 July-October (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Gates, Horatio Papers] Resolutions of Harvard, 18 June 1779 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Gates, Horatio Papers] Society of Cincinnati, 1785 December 10 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Guion Family Papers (MS 3013)], 1892, 1898, Undated (Oversize medium)
    See the finding aid for the Guion family papers (MS 3013) for item content.
  - [Y-Dr. Charles Hale] Certificates, 1827-1834 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Joanna Hallett] Grace A. Wixom Diplomas, 1899-1909 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Hare Family Papers] Diplomas and Photos- Montgomery Hale, 1870-1932 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Jacob Harvey Family Papers (MS 306)], 1846-1847, 1947 (Oversize small)
    Includes Supplement to the Dublin Evening Post (26 March 1946), the Dublin Evening Post (31 July 1847), and U.S. Department of the Interior Geological Survey map of the Vanderbilt Mansion Historic Site in New York (stamped 1st Proof, June 1947).
  - [Y-Shirley Hayes Papers] Washington Square Park, undated (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Hendricks Family Papers (MS 295)] Belleville Copper Photograph, undated (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Horticultural Society of New York Records (MS 3033)], 1960s-1996 (Oversize large)
    Includes oversize items from the Hort collection: New York Flower Show and other posters, floor plans of the New York Coliseum and other plans related to the Flower Shows, and a set of plans for the Vanderlip estate.
  - [Y-Hyde, James Hazen, Papers. MS 319] (2 folders), 1917 (Oversize small, medium)
    2 folders: 1 small oversize, the other medium. Oversize small includes photographs and certificates. Oversize medium includes a poster, in French, for event at Nantes at which Hyde spoke; this is folder 2 of 2 of material for this event. The first folder includes Hyde's remarks. See the finding aid for the Hyde papers.
  - [Y-Itzler Collection] Certificates, 1860-1929 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Kendrick, Henry L.], 1831-1868 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-King, Rufus papers] Appointments, commissions, and other documents issued to Rufus and John Alsop King. 15 items., 1796-1825 (Oversize small)
    Contains presidential signatures, among them George Washington and John Adams.
  - [Y-Louis Kuhn] Certificates, 1875-1881 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Martha J. Lamb Papers] Art, Undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Martha J. Lamb Papers] Certificates, 1888-1889, Undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Martha J. Lamb Papers] Christmas Songs and List, Undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-John Laurance Papers] Appointment of John Laurance as Judge of the New York District Court, 1794 May 6 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Le Boutillier Family Papers] Artwork and Portfolio, undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Lefferts-Wetherill Family Papers] Certificates and printed material, 1848-1919 (Oversize medium)
    Folder contains mounted Civil War documents of Tennessee Union soldier Joseph B. Wetherill (including Oath of Allegiance to the United States); Samuel Wetherill's certificate of membership in the Zelosophic Society; John Wetherill's appointment as a delegate to the Antietam Battlefield Board; and several other appointments and certificates.
  - [Y-Lefferts Wetherill Family Papers] Certificate in latin issued to Samuel Wetherill, undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Lockman, DeWitt M.] Inventory (Christian) Books, Undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Low, Fleming, and King family papers (MS 3091)], 1861 August 17 (Oversize small)
    Commission of Cornelius Low King as First Lieutenant in the 14th Regiment of Infantry. Signed by U.S. President Abraham Lincoln and Secretary of War Simon Cameron. (Gift of Noëlle King and the King Family, 2019.)
  - [Y-Luce, Henry, Papers. (MS 3014)] (10 folders), 1939-1965 (Oversize small)
    Includes various oversize items from the Henry R. Luce papers. See the Luce finding aid for details.
  - [Y-Luce, Henry, Papers. (MS 3014)] (2 folders), 1912-1913, 1941 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Luce, Henry, Papers. (MS 3014)], circa 1933-1949 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Martin Family] Certificates, 1890-1925 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McAneny Collection] Photographs, undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McBean Collection] Apple, Vauderburgh, Bickley Indenture, 1715 June 2 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McBean Collection] Gilbert Livingston Commission, 1769 August 9 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McBean Collection] Indentures, 1785 December (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-McBean Collection] Land Grant- Remsen and Brinckerhoff, signed by George Clinton, 1786 May 12 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-McBean Collection] Morris Deed, 1772 May 25 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McBean Collection] Muhlenburgh Deed, 1759 January 15 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McBean Collection] Morris Commission- Superintendant of Roads, 1799 February 26 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McComb Papers] Orders for Marble for City Hall, 1808 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Documents, 1780-1781 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Documents, 1756-1772 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Documents, 1776 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Documents, 1777 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Hospital Plans, 1782 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Inventories and Letters, 1782-1786 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Kosciuszko Drawings of West Point Forts and Returns, 1779, Undated (Oversize large)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Letters, List of Officers, Death Warrant, 1778 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Morning Reports, 1776 May (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Muster Rolls and Pay Extract, 1776 May (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Muster Rolls and Pay and Sick Reports, 1776 June (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Morning Reports, 1776 June (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Morning Reports, 1776 July-August (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Muster Rolls and Pay Reports, 1776 July (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Muster Rolls and Pay Reports, 1776 August (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Muster Rolls and Pay Reports, 1776 September (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Muster Rolls and Pay Reports, 1776 October (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Muster Rolls and Pay Reports, 1776 November (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Muster Rolls and Pay Reports, 1776 December (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Non-Importation Agreement Papers, 1770 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Report of the Barrack Guard and Monthly Return, 1775 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-McDougall Papers] Returns and Letters, 1779 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-McKesson Papers] Roll of persons taking Oath of Allegiance (Jewish names), 1741 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-McVickar Family] Diplomas and Certificates, 1865-1908 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Mitchell, Edward] Certificates, 1890 January 27 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Murra, Laura Shaw. MS 3142]. Posters, 1992-2003 (Oversize medium)
    Oversize posters from Murra collection on feminism (MS 3142); see that finding aid for item list.
  - [Y-Nathan, Edgar J, Jr. MS 438] (2 folders), 1876-1961 (Oversize small)
    See Edgar J. Nathan Papers finding aid for details of content.
  - [Y-Nathan, Edgar J, Jr. MS 438], circa 1930s-1940s (Oversize large)